

Baikov Alexey

02.01.1987 (35 years)

Python backend developer

Level: Junior, Junior+ Employment: full time

Work schedule: remote working, full day

Salary expectations: \$1300

Contacts

- +7 (929) 053-73-35
- https://t.me/alexbaikov
- alex@baikov.dev
- https://github.com/baikov
- Nizhny Novgorod, Russia

Work Experience

february 2021 − present (1 year)

Learning new stack

I applied all the studied technologies in practice (project allflags.ru)

A short list of practical skills:

- · VPS administration, work with Heroku, AWS, Yandex.Cloud;
- · Configuring Nginx, Traefik, Prometheus, Grafana;
- Working with Docker and Docker Compose, basics of CI/CD;
- Codestyle (flake8, black), testing (pytest, coverage), documenting (Sphinx);
- · Working with version control and workflows (git, github, git-flow, github-flow);
- · Working with Django, DRF, PostgreSQL, Redis, Celery, Flower.

PKF Luidor, Nizhny Novgorod (Car factory / special vehicles)

Web developer, SEO specialist

- Developed a service for finding spare parts by VIN (backend: Django/DRF, frontend: Vue.js);
- · Development and SEO of the company's websites on 1C-Bitrix;
- · More than 3 years of experience in remote work.
- april 2012 october 2015 (3 years 7 months)

Freelance, own projects

Full-stack developer, SEO specialist

- · Website development and SEO (Joomla, WordPress, 1C-Bitrix, OpenCart).
- 🔷 🐞 september 2011 april 2012 (1 year 1 month)

Redox, Moscow (commerce / health products)

Product Manager

september 2008 — april 2011 (2 years 7 months)

Redox, Nizhny Novgorod (retail / health products)

Sales Manager

■ november 2006 — may 2008 (1 year 7 months)

Telma Soft, Nizhny Novgorod (software development)

Trainee engineer in the software development and testing department

· Internship while studying at the university

About

I love web development. More than 10 years of experience in website development and SEO helped me to acquire skills in frontend, backend, DevOps and project managment. I hope that the new stack and deepening in the backend will allow me to participate in the development of larger and more interesting projects.

My objectives for this year: to start a career as a backend developer in a modern company and grow to the Middle level.

Education

LOBACHEVSKY SUNN

Lobachevsky State University of Nizhny Novgorod

id 2004-2009 (5 years), full time, specialist

Faculty of Computational Mathematics and Cybernetics

Specialty: **Applied Mathematics** and **Informatics**

Qualification: mathematician, system programmer

Навыки



Languages

Russian Native English Intermediate

Courses

Docker | 2021, slurm.io

Build a Backend REST API with Python & Django | 2021, Udemi

Algorithms and Data Structures in Python 3 | 2021, YouTube

Projects

Country flags

front

Search parts by VIN

Books

Python Tricks, Dan Bader
Grokking Algorithms, Aditya Bhargava
Practices of the Python Pro, Dane Hillard
Django 3.0. The practice of developing
websites in python, Dronov V. A.